# Michael J. Turley

mike.turley@alum.cs.umass.edu — 781-264-6283 — 208 Prospect St, Athol, MA 01331 github.com/mturley — twitter.com/mundanedetail — linkedin.com/in/mturley

#### **OVERVIEW**

Michael is a pragmatic and creative software engineer with over 7 years of experience in web and mobile application development, systems architecture, DevOps, QA, graphics, databases, and IT. He is building the new open enterprise with the help of Red Hat and the FOSS community.

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science Spring 2015 University of Massachusetts Amherst Amherst, MA Dean's List Student – Member: UMass ACM, CS Recruiting and Outreach Committee

### COMPUTER SKILLS

Languages

Web Tools (Client)

Web Tools (Server)

Databases

Infrastructure Tools

Operating Systems

Design Software

Scala, Java, C/C++, JavaScript, Python, Ruby, PHP, HTML5/CSS3

NPM, Webpack, Gulp, Bower, React, Angular, jQuery, Meteor

Nginx, Play Framework, Akka, Node.js, Rails, Wordpress, Meteor

MySQL/SQLite/Postgres, MongoDB, Elasticsearch, Vertica, DynamoDB

Jenkins, Ansible, Chef, Amazon EC2/S3, DigitalOcean, Linode, Heroku

GNU/Linux, Mac OS X, Windows, Android, iOS

IATEX, Photoshop, Illustrator, AfterEffects, Premiere, Maya

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Red Hat, Inc.

November 2017 - Present

UI Front End Developer, CloudForms/PatternFly (US ENG UXD R&D) Westford, MA

- Developing React components for PatternFly (patternfly.org)
- Maintaining and Modernizing the UI for ManageIQ (manageiq.org)
- Helping to produce Red Hat CloudForms (redhat.com/cloudforms) based on ManageIQ

# Hewlett Packard Enterprise

February 2015 - November 2017

Software Engineer, InfoSight / StoreFront Remote (HPE Storage Analytics) Andover, MA

- Built and maintained many high-profile features for HPE InfoSight (infoSight.hpe.com)
- Worked heavily at all levels of the stack using JavaScript, Scala, Play, Akka and more
- Collaborated with and learned from a small Scrum team of HP engineers and architects
- Contributed heavily to a major UI integration upon HPE's aquisition of Nimble Storage

## Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Summer 2014

SDE Intern, AWS Storage Gateway (aws.amazon.com/storagegateway) Cambridge, MA

- Developed a new Amazon-internal website for Gateway support using Ruby on Rails
- Enhanced customer-facing diagnostic and logging tools using Java and Bash

## NimbleBot.com Interactive Software & Digital Design

2011-2013

Contract Web Application Developer in Javascript, PHP & MySQL

Cambridge, MA

- Designed and developed round-trip and real-time web apps and REST APIs
- Took a leadership role on a team of 4 developers to build, debug, and deploy
- Interfaced with clients and prepared deliverable reports

# Learn360.com K-12 Education Multimedia

Spring 2011

Software Tester & Frontend Prototype Developer

Woodbury, NY

• Tested for regressions and built patches for proposed improvements to the UI

### ResNet Resource Center at Northeastern University

PC Repair Technician & Service Tool Developer

2008-2009 Boston, MA

• Collaborated with a team of technicians on service-related projects and tools

# INTERESTS

Hobby programming projects, experimenting with new languages and platforms Music composition and performance on bass/vocals (facebook.com/NonZeroChance) and piano Skiing, snowboarding, hiking, swimming, and running